Guide to the Clayton Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Clayton papers
1589-1824
OSB MSS 40
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2
(4 boxes)
Papers documenting Clayton's and Morris's work as scriveners. The papers include receipts, indentures, money orders, notes, and short letters to Clayton and Morris. Some bear the signatures of Clayton and Morris.
Other Storage Formats: Oversize
Clayton, Robert, Sir, 1629-1707
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Please consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This finding aid encompasses accessions of materials pertaining to Robert Clayton and John Morris.
Indentures; Money orders; Receipts (financial records); Scriveners (Law) -- England -- London; Clayton, Robert, Sir, 1629-1707; Morris, John, ca. 1627-1682
- Papers documenting the work of Clayton and Morris
  - Apsley, Sir Allen, 1616-1683.
    - 14 ALS, 1 receipt, 1 money order to Robert Clayton and staff and "a schedule of Rents Parcell of the Dutchy of Lancast. Conveyed to Sir Allen Apsley by the King's Command," [v.p.], 1660 Aug 20-1679 Aug 23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Indenture, 1670 Apr 2
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Oversize, folder 134
  - Apsley, Sir Peter, [1679] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aram, Thomas. Indenture, 1671 Jun 26
    See: Oversize, folder 135
  - Ayliffe, George. DS acknowledging the receipt of legacy from Francis Englefield., 1670 Dec 14 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Becher, Henry. 4 ALS to John Morris, [v.p.], 1675 Jan 20-1676 Apr 17 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Belke, William. Receipt, [n.p.], 1663 Nov 9 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Scope and Contents
    Countersigned by Edward Fane.
  - Berkshire, Charles Howard, 2d Earl of, ca. 1615-1679
    - AL to Alderman Blackwell, [n.p.], 1670 May 9 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - AL to Robert Clayton, [n.p.], 1674 Mar 3 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Indentures, 1661-1670
      See: Oversize, folders 136-138
  - Berkshire, Thomas Howard, 1st Earl of, ca. 1590-1659
    - Indentures, [n.p.], 1656-58
      See: Oversize, folders 139-141
    - 1 ALS, to Robert Clayton and John Morris, 1662 Apr 9 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - DS to John Brewster, [n.p.], 1661 Jun 29 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Empowering John Morris and Robert Clayton to collect certain sums in payment of a loan to Howard. Damaged.
    - DS, London, 1661 Apr 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Bond to Sir Robert Clayton.
    - DS, [n.p.], 1662 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Receipt for monies from Clayton and Morris.
  - Berkshire, Thomas Howard, 3d Earl of, ca. 1619-1706.
    - DS (in Latin), [n.p.], 1677 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 6 ALS to Robert Clayton and John Morris, 3 bills for "writings done", 1667-1689 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Beverly, Sir James, fl. 1660. 10 ALS to Robert Clayton and John Morris, [v.p.], 1659 Feb 12-1672 Nov 14 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bretland, R. 4 ALS to John Morris, [n.p.], 1675 Jan 11-1677 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Buckingham, George Villiers, Duke of, 1628-1687. ALS to Mr. Morris. Gardiner's Accounts: Henry Story., 1667 Sep 16-1684 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Carter, Richard, d. 1692. 3 ALS to Thomas Browne, Robert Clayton, and John Morris, [n.p.], 1672-76 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Concerning naval matters.
  - Charlton, Mr. ALS to John Morris., 1676 Jul 8 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Clarendon, Henry Hyde, 2d Earl of, 1638-1709. ALS to Robert Clayton, London, 1674 Feb (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Clayton, Robert, Sir Robert, 1629-1707
    - 5 indentures, [n.p.], 1661-62
      See: Oversize, folders 142-146
    - Receipt to Ambrose Holbeck, [n.p.], 1664 Jan 2 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Clitherow, James. 3 ALS, 19 money drafts, [n.p.], 1661 Jan 2-1677 Oct 11 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Business correspondence to Thomas Browne, Robert Clayton, and John Morris.
  - Crane, William. 7 money orders, 1 receipt, [n.p.], 1661 Jun 26-1665 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Business correspondence to Thomas Browne, Robert Clayton, and John Morris. Sworn statement on reverse of Crane to Clayton and Morris, 1663 Jul 22.
  - Crispe, Thomas. ALS to Robert Clayton., 1660 Jul 17 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Fane, Sir Francis, d. 1691. 12 ALS to Robert Clayton and John Morris and an undated memorial on behalf of Fane, [v.p.], 1664 Apr 13-1674 Nov 25 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Fane, Sir Francis, fl. 1626. ALS to Sir Francis Fane (son), Fulbeck, 1672 Nov 23 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Graham, Ronald. ALS to Mr. Clayton, 1677 Nov 24 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Grahme, Ranald. 23 ALS, 2 money orders, [n.p.], 1663 Jul 15-1678 Mar 11 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Business correspondence to Lord Carlisle, Peter Clayton, Robert Clayton, Ranald Grahme, John Morris.
  - Hall, John. 12 ALS, 2 receipts, [n.p.], 1672 Feb 8-1682 Jun 16 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Business correspondence with Thomas Browne, Robert Clayton, and John Morris.
  - Hall, William. 1 receipt., 1660 Feb 12 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Hardy, Robert. ALS on behalf of Mr. Hungate., 1674 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Harris, C. 3 ALS to Robert Clayton, [v.p.], 1673-74 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Heneage, Lady Faith. 8 ALS to Robert Clayton and John Morris, [n.p.], 1671 Jun 5-1677 Jul 23 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Hodgkinson, William. 8 ALS to Robert Clayton, Thomas Gorman, and John Morris, [n.p.], 1675 Oct 26-1677 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Holbech, Ambrose. 4 ALS to Robert Clayton and John Morris, [n.p.], 1661 Apr 1-1676 Jul 3 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Houghton, John, fl. 1669-1695. 2 ALS 2 DS, [n.p.], 1669-95 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Houghton, Robert. 11 ALS, 2 DS, [n.p.], 1669-77 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Howard, Bernard. 1 ALS., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Howard, Cathrine. Autograph, n.p., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Howard, Henry. DS to Robert Abbott., 1654 Feb 22 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Howard, Lady. 1 receipt., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Howard, Lord. An account of his holdings in Yorkshire, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Howard, P. ALS to Alderman., 6 Nov (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Howard, Sir Robert, 1626-1698
    - ALS to Sir Robert Clayton, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Mounted.
    - 3 bonds, London?, 1697 Jun 5, Nov 24 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - DS to Arthur Capel, Earl of Essex, London, 1674 Dec 7 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      Mutilated.
  - Essex, Arthur Capel, 1st Earl of, 1631-1683. Signature, London, 1679 Jun 5 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Fragment of a letter to Robert Howard.
  - Howard, Robert.
    - ALS, 2 receipts, 1661 May 6-1692 Nov 6 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Petition of Horatio Townsend to the King., 1671 Oct (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Howard, Thomas. 1 receipt., 1695 Jan 1 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Howard of Escrick, William Howard, Baron. ALS and receipt., 1663 May 14, 1667 Jan 6 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Humfrey, Edmund
    - 2 ALS, 18 drafts, [n.p.], 1659 May 19-1664 Oct 25 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      - Business correspondence with Thomas Browne, Robert Clayton, and John Morris.
  - 2 ALS to John Sandford, Esheen, 1663 Aug 4. Both of same date. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Hungate family. 50 ALS from Sir Henry Hungate, his son Henry, and daughter, Lucy, to Robert Clayton and John Morris, [v.p.], 1623, 1673-1676, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Huxley, Elizabeth. 1 ALS, 2 LS to Thomas Browne and John Morris, [n.p.], 1662-63 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Huxley, James. 2 ALS, 8 money orders, 1 receipt to Thomas Browne and John Morris, [n.p.], 1658 Jul 19-1664 Jun 8 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Huxley, Sir John, fl. 1663. 11 money orders to Thomas Browne and John Morris, [n.p.], 1660 Mar 16-1663 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Ives, James. 6 ALS to Robert Clayton, Peter Clayton, and John Morris, [n.p.], 1671 Oct 12-1676 Feb 6 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Lauderdale, John Maittans, 2nd earl of. 1 bill., 1668 May 3 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Lightfoot, Francis. 4 ALS to Robert Clayton and John Morris, [n.p.], 1674 Jan 19-1675 Feb 17 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Lockwood, Richard. 8 ALS to John Morris and a copy of Lockwood's marriage settlement on Margaret Susan Cutts, [n.p.], 1671 Feb 12-1676 May 1 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Long, Sir Walter, fl. 1625. 20 ALS, 1 receipt, [n.p.], 1659 Jun 1-1672 Oct 1 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Lulls, George. 3 ALS, 6 money drafts to Thomas Browne, John Burton, Robert Clayton, and John Morris, [n.p.], 1659 Feb-1677 Nov 17 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Meggs, William. 16 ALS, 1 contract draft, and 4 money orders, [n.p.], 1662 Dec 9-1677 Jan 20 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Morris, John d. 1682. Indenture, [n.p.], 1661 Jul 25
    See: Oversize, folder 146
  - Palmer, Edward. 4 ALS to Robert Clayton and James Clitherow, 1 money order, 1 contract (draft) with Robert Clayton, and 1 bill "for writings," [v.p.], 1664 Dec 22-1678 May 1 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Palmer, Ralph. 2 ALS relating to the will of Dr. Hamey, 1677 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Palmer, William. 2 bonds., 1649, 1653 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Palmes, John. 2 bonds, 1671 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Phillips, Richard. Letter to his landlord, John Morris., 1674 Aug 1 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Poynter, John., 1663 Apr (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Poyntz, Sir John, fl. 1666. 3 ALS to Robert Clayton and John Morris, 1 D, 1 bond, and 1 note? concerning him, [n.p.], 1671 Aug-1675 Mar (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Pride, Thomas. d. 1658. (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Draft of an indenture, 1656 Dec 19
    - 1 bill and copy., 1656 Jun 6 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Rivers, Richard Savage, 4th Earl of, 1660?-1712
    - ALS and receipt to Robert Clayton, [n.p.], 1664 Apr 1-1677 Mar 11 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - ALS to William Wyatt, [n.p.], 1677 Dec 10 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Rockingham, Edward Watson, 2d Baron of, 1630-1689. Business correspondence to Robert Clayton and John Morris, [v.p.], 1654 Jul 25-1665 Jun 5 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Rockingham, Lady Eleanor (Manners), fl. 1662. ALS to John Morris, [n.p.], 1660 Apr 25 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Sandford, John. 5 ALS to Robert Clayton and John Morris, [v.p.], 1672 Sep 2-1676 Oct 30 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    Receipt added on an ALS from Edmund Humfrey to Thomas Browne.
  - Sandford, Edward. ALS to John Morris, [n.p.], 1676 Sep 20 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Sandford, Mary. ALS to John Morris, [n.p.], 1676 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Sandford, Thomas, fl. 1719. D in manuscript (draft), London, 1719 Jun 30 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    Complaint to the Lord High Chancellor by John Maynard and Thomas Sandford, merchants of London, against Jasper Cullum, linendraper.
  - Saunders, Thomas. 4 ALS to John Morris, [n.p.], 1673 Oct 17-Nov 22 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Sayers, John. 12 ALS, 5 money orders, 1 receipt, [n.p.], 1662 Oct 24-1676 Aug 11 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    Business correspondence to Thomas Browne, Robert Clayton and John Morris.
  - Scroggs, Sir William, 1623?-1683. ALS to Robert Clayton, London, 1671 Dec 4 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Scrope, Adrian. 1 account sheet., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Sherard, William, Lord. 2 DS., 1638 Dec 1, 1673 Jul 11 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Somaster, Dorothy. 3 receipts., 1631-39 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Somerscales, Joseph. DS to William Hartupp, 1671 Oct 17 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Somerfeild, Thomas. DS to William Hartupp., 1646 Jun (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Somerford, S. 6 ALS to Sir Thomas Bludworth, 1678-79 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Southcote, K. ALS to Marie Wyes of Totness, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Stafford, Willliam. 2 DS, 3 receipts, 23 money orders, and 1 account sheet for 1664 Jul 23 with a receipt in French on the reverse, [n.p.], 1653 Jun 5-1665 Jun 2 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Stone, John
    - D (petition to the king), [n.p.], 1686 Feb 3 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - 1 ALS, 29 money orders to Thomas Browne, Robert Clayton, and John Morris, [v.p.], 1657 May 19-1674 Jan 17 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Stringer, Sir Thomas, fl. 1669. ALS to John Morris, [n.p.], 1672 Jul 14 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Suffolk and Berkshire, Henry Howard. ALS to William Lee., 1750 May 23 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Talbot, Sir John, fl. 1660. 2 ALS, 1 receipt, 12 money orders, [n.p.], 1660 May 11-1671 May 12 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Thompson, John. DS, [n.p.], 1661 Jul (Box 3, Folder 97)
    Agreement with William Crane.
  - Thornton, Arthur. 4 ALS to Peter Clayton, York, 1677 Feb 25-1678 Jul 8 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Tresham, George. 9 ALS, 2 money orders, [n.p.], 1663-1676 May 18 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    Business correspondence to Thomas Burton, Peter Clayton, and Robert Clayton.
  - Tresham, Lady Anna. 9 Als to Peter Clayton, Robert Clayton, and John Morris, [n.p.], 1671 Jun 10-1675 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Warcupp, Bridgett. ALS to Robert Clayton, [n.p.], 1660 Oct (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Warcupp, Edmond
    - ALS to Richard Southwell, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - 13 money drafts to Thomas Browne and Robert Clayton, [n.p.], 1659 Sep 17-1665 Jul 6 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Warcupp, Henry. Money order to Thomas Browne, [n.p.], 1659 Mar 7 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Warcupp, Robert. 4 ALS to Thomas Browne and Robert Clayton, [n.p.], 1660 Oct-1671 Oct 28 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Whitgrave Family. 20 ALS and 1 AL (fragment, undated) to Robert Clayton or his assistant Leman, from members of the Whitgrave Family [n.p.], 1671 Jan 2-1676 Apr 15 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    Concerning the care of one of Clayton's country estates.
  - Williamson, Sir Joseph. 3 ALS to Robert Clayton, Whitehall, 1672 Aug, Sep 9 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Willoughby of Parham, Lord Francis. Draft of two letters to Roger Osborn, Governor of Montsenat, and to Col. J. Russell, Governor of Nevis., 1660 Feb (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Wintour, John. ALS to Robert Clayton, [n.p.], 1663 Mar 9 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Woodcock, Peter. 8 ALS, [n.p.], 1662 Apr 21-Sep 20 (Box 3, Folder 110)
- Other papers, 1685
  - "An Abstract of the Accompt of the Clerke or Keeper of the Hannaper in Chancery for one yeare from Michas 1684 to Michas 1685. (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Autographs, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Cockburn, Sir James. DS to Mr. Elliott. An account of the East India Election., 1765 Apr 4 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Derby, James Stanley, Earl of, 1607-51.
    - Genealogical charts, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Marriage contract, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Dorset, John Frederick Sackville, Duke of. Warrant for his appointment as comptroller of the Royal household., 1794 Apr 27 (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Dunstanville, Lord., 1801 Jan 12 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Glen, Alex. ALS to "Dear Sir" requesting a commission into the East India Service for his brother., 1765 Apr 29 (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Harvard, John. Receipt of monies from John Gooch., 1789 May 20 (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Howard, Charles. Affidavit., 1752 Feb 11 (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - Howard, Joseph. ALS to Thomas Newell, 1754 Feb 8 (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - "In Mr. Howard's Chamber at the Reference", 1666 May 26 (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Indenture fragment. (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - "Perticular of Durham Yard.", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Pourret, C. ALS to "My dear friend", 1707 Jun 17 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Rutland, Edward, Earl of. "A Coppy of ye Certificate concerning the evidence of Edward, late Earle of Rutland.", 5 Dec 1589 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Scheckenbourg, Baron de. ALS to Mr. Arthur Lee., 1777 Jun 29 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Slade, William. ALS from Fairfax Moresby., 1824 Mar 13 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - "A Table to the Booke or the head or Title Page of Severall Discourses herein.", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - "Third part of the head Prophet Habbakuk", (in Latin), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Transcripts of letters., 1821 May 29 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Unidentified seal., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Walpole, Robert, Sir. 1 autograph, 2 receipts., 1738-40, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 133)
- Oversize
  - Apsley, Sir Allen, 1616-1683.
    - Indenture, 1670 Apr 2 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 134)
  - Aram, Thomas.
    - Indenture, 1671 Jun 26 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 135)
  - Berkshire, Charles Howard, 2d Earl of, ca. 1615-1679
    - Indentures, 1661-1670 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 136-138)
  - Berkshire, Thomas Howard, 1st Earl of, ca. 1590-1659
    - Indentures, 1656-1658 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 139-141)
  - Clayton, Robert, Sir Robert, 1629-1707
    - 5 indentures, [n.p.], 1661-62 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 142-146)